hi and welcome back to Plating It with
Wendy where we share with you recipes
which impress with ease as I glaze this
ham with sweet honey and fragrant spices
I can already picture it at the center
of the table ready to bring everyone
together now let's get started for this
recipe we're going to go in with a 10 lb
fully cooked smoked ham which is bone in
and you could either go in for one that
is spiral cut but I've opted for one
that's not now we're going to take off
this vacuum plastic seal and start
prepping the ham and now we're going to
score it so that when we baste it with
the glaze the flavor of the glaze goes
right into the meat if you buy a spiral
cut ham there's no need to do this
step and now we're going to do the same
thing on this side as well
now that we've scored the ham let's keep
it aside and prep our baking tray so
we're first going to go in with some
pineapple slices at the bottom of the
tray and this is going to flavor the ham
and also keep it nice and succulent and
now we're just going to start lining it
up all across the bottom of the tray the
pineapple slices will also get
caramelized while the ham is in the oven
and then we're going to use them to
decorate the dish when we serve the ham
we're going to use all this pineapple
juice to prepare the glaze but first
let's place the ham on top of the
pineapple slices and when placing the
ham in the baking tray you're going to
place it cut side down we're just going
to toss in some few star into our baking
dish for some added
flavor to add some warm flavors to the
glaze we're going to be adding 1/4
teaspoon of ground cloves so we're just
going to grind up a few in our motor
pristol before we go over to the stove
and prepare the glaze
while preparing the glaze it's a good
time to preheat your oven to 325° F or
163° C and to a pot on low heat we're
going to add 1/4 cup of unsalted butter
and now that the butter has melted we're
going to add 1 cup of the pineapple
juice that we had preserved earlier 1
cup of packed dark brown
sugar and that's how packed you want it
2 tablebspoon of Dijon mustard and this
adds a lot of flavor to the glaze half a
cup of honey or you could add maple
syrup if you wanted and for those warm
flavors we're going to go in with 1/4
teaspoon of the ground cloves 1/4
teaspoon of ground cinnamon and 1/4
teaspoon of freshly grated nutmeg now
we're going to increase the heat to
medium high and we're going to allow
this to cook for about 6 to 8 minutes
till it thickens make sure that you keep
stirring it while you cook it so that it
does not stick to the bottom of the pot
so it's going to start bubbling up a lot
so you've got to keep stirring it and
when cooking ham you don't need to add
any salt that's why we added the
unsalted butter because the pre-cooked
ham already contains a lot of salt in
it the glaze is beginning to thicken it
requires just about another 2 or 3
minutes to cook before we take it off
the heat
now this is the consistency you're
looking
for and it's going to thicken more while
it cools so now we're going to take it
off the heat and we're going to take a
brush and put it into that lovely glaze
that we made now from the top we're
going to start basting it down with the
glaze and you're going to be really
generous when doing
this and you're going to do it all
around the ham don't forget to put some
on the top as well here you're going to
use up at least one/3 of the glaze that
you prepare while doing the first
basting we're going to base it twice
more once we have placed it in the oven
for the first time to preserve the
moisture in the ham we're going to
loosely cover it with an aluminum foil
before we place it in our preheated oven
at 325° F or 160° C
and we're going to bake it till the
internal temperature of the ham reaches
100° F which is approximately 38° C and
this should take somewhere between 2 to
2 and 1/2 hours once the ham has reached
the desired internal temperature it's
time to take it out of the oven and
remove the aluminum foil and now we're
going to baseaste it once again with the
glaze that we had made and this time
we're going to use half of what is
remaining and while you're doing this
you're going to crank up the heat of the
oven to 400° F which is approximately
200°
C you'll find that the glaze has
thickened you could always warm it and
thin it out a bit i prefer dabbing on
the thick glaze this is going to be the
centerpiece at the table now this is
going to help caramelize the outside and
give it that lovely crispy look now back
into the oven this goes for 10 minutes
then we'll take it out and baste it one
more
time it's been 10 minutes so now it's
time for us to baste it one more time
and now we're going to use up all the
remaining glaze to baste it the second
time you're going to try to get it
between all those cuts that we had made
so that the flavor goes into the
ham just going to use the brush and pat
it down very gently now let's put some
at the back don't forget the top portion
you want the flavor all over now back
into the oven this goes uncovered for
another 10
minutes our ham is ready but not so
ready you've got to let it rest for at
least 30 minutes before you carve it wow
look at all that pineapple in the bottom
it's so full of flavor and we're going
to be using them when we plate the ham
and all those drippings that are down in
the pan we can put it into a gravy bowl
and keep it at the side of the ham so
that if anybody wants to pour it on the
top of the slice they can always do that
because it's loaded with flavor oh my
goodness look at that and now it's time
to give the ham a taste and I'm so
excited it's looking absolutely
delicious but before we do that if
you're new to my channel or haven't
subscribed already but enjoy trying out
recipes that turn out right every time
you're at the right place so go ahead
press that subscribe button and while
you're at it if you hit the bell icon
you'll be the first to get notified
every time I upload a new video okay now
let's give the ham a taste and I'm just
going to taste a small bit but if you
want to see me carve it you're going to
have to join me for lunch on Sunday just
a small bit look at
that
wow absolutely amazing
m wow i'm actually speechless this ham
is so amazing that I cannot find the
words to describe it so for the full
recipe check out the link in the
description box below thanks for
watching see you soon