these quick and easy tuna cakes are
tender delicious and loaded with flavor
hi you're watching plating it to Wendy
where I share with you recipes which
impress with these these tuna cakes come
together in minutes so let's get started
for this recipe we're going to be using
three cans of solid white tuna if you
have flaky tuna handy that would work
too you could even use salmon if you
want it for this recipe we're going to
drain out all the water
let's empty the tuner into a bowl and
we're going to mix all the ingredients
in this
bowl since we're using solid tuner we're
going to smash it down so that it
becomes a little bit more
[Music]
flaky I think this is looking just right
to help the tuna cakes bind together
we're going to be using the breadcrumbs
of three slices of fresh bread we're
just going to cut it down so we can put
it into our little mini chopper and make
it into
breadcrumbs I love using fresh
breadcrumbs for this recipe because it
gives the tuna cakes that lovely tender
texture since the onion is really huge
I'm going to go in with half an onion
I'm just going to cut the onion up into
big bits and then toss it into the
chopper and chop it up
fine this is my favorite hack for
chopping onions now let's toss the
onions into the bowl
for a little spice we're going to be
adding in two green
[Music]
chilies I'm just going to give this to a
rough chop and add it to the
chopper along with the chilies I'm going
to add about five garlic cloves and I'm
just going to clean them and add them to
the
chopper just going to add this along
with the rest of the
ingredients for that extra EXT ra flavor
and a pop of color we're going to be
adding half a red bell pepper just going
to give it a rough chop I'm going to be
putting this two into the
chopper now let's tosson the bell
peppers along with the
rest now to make our tuna cakes nice and
moist we're going to be adding in two
Tomatoes but we're going to take out the
seeds because we don't want them getting
too mushy I decided not to put the
tomatoes into the chopper because it
tends to become a little bit more pasty
in the chopper I feel that chopping it
by hand keeps it a little bit more
firm now let's add this to the bowl to
give our tuna cakes that nice fresh
flavor we're going to add in a bunch of
cantro and we're going to chop it down
nice and fine just going to add that in
with the rest of the ingredients let's
season this up with a juice of half a
lemon about half a teaspon of Dijon
mustard some salt
and pepper to
taste now to bring this all together and
help it to bind we're going to add three
large
eggs we're just going to give the eggs a
light beet because that's going to make
it easier for it to mix up to the rest
of the
ingredients just going to lightly mix up
all these ingredients first before we
add the eggs to
[Music]
it the burst of all these colors is
going to make the tuna cakes look so
delicious just once they're fried and
ready now let's just add the egg
in we're just going to give this a good
mix so the egg gets a chance to bind all
of the ingredients together these tuna
cakes are so delicious and really easy
to put together they can be prepared
just in time when you want to eat them
or they can be prepared ahead of time
too and refrigerated and then had just
when you need them okay this looks just
perfect so now let's start forming the
tuner cakes in a bowl we're going to
beat up three eggs we're going to be
dipping the cakes into the beaten eggs
before we coat it with the bread crumbs
just going to put some breadcrumbs down
on this and I'm going to use a trigger
release ice cream scoop just so that we
get uniform size of tuna cakes you don't
need to do it okay so we dipped it into
the egg and now straight into the bread
crumbs
Now using a knife I'm just going to
shape it
[Music]
down just going to lift it and keep it
to one side while we prepare the next
[Music]
one again into the beaten
egg and then into the bread
crumbs coat it well with the breadcrumbs
all
[Music]
around just going to form it
again keep it to one side we're going to
be frying these in batches of four so as
soon as you have four prepped add some
vegetable oil to a heated Skillet and
let's fry
them since the only thing that needs to
really cook in these tuna cakes is the
egg it doesn't take too long to fry as
soon as you find that it's golden brown
in one side you're going to flip it over
and allow it to fry on the other
side once they get that lovely golden
color on both sides we're going to lift
them off the pan and place them in a
plate on a paper towel so that any
excess oil will be absorbed
now let's plate these crispy tuna
cakes and look at
that now let's give these delicious tuna
cakes a
taste it's nice and crispy on the
outside and it's nice and soft on the
inside wow and all the burst of colors
all the peppers and the
Tomato m
hey and before I go if you're new to my
Channel or haven't subscribed already
subscribe and don't forget to hit on
that Bell icon because then you'll get a
notification every time I upload a new
video if you enjoy watching my videos
don't forget to give me a big thumbs up
and leave me your comments below follow
me on Facebook Instagram and Tik Tok the
information is in the description below
thanks for watching see you soon